Sonika Finch

848 Spring Street NW Apt. 907 Atlanta, GA 30308 | U.S. Citizen | Singapore Citizen (831) 233-1996 | sonika.finch1@gmail.com | https://sonikaf.github.io/

Objective

Internationally experienced software engineer with 3+ years of developing high-quality object-oriented code in multiple languages. Excellent communication and collaborative skills proven by leading an interdisciplinary team of seven Georgia Tech students in a 4-month scrum environment DBMS project for the non-profit H.E.R.O. for Children. A driven, quick learner that enjoys complex challenges and staying constantly curious. Currently seeking full time employment starting Summer of 2018.

Education

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY | COLLEGE OF COMPUTING | ATLANTA, GA

- · Major: Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Overall GPA: 3.34 | Major GPA: 3.59
- August 2014 May 2018 (Expected)

· Threads: People & Information Internetworks

Experience

PROTIVITI - ATLANTA, GA

Intern, Data & Analytics- Business Intelligence Solution

June 2017 - August 2017

- · Created flexible and informative business intelligence reporting dashboards with jQuery custom components for Protiviti's executive use
- · This project will save Protiviti about \$300,000 a year by automating the manual data reporting that was the practice
- · Worked as a consultant to redesign Nielsen's business intelligence system- personally focused on data warehousing and ETL to the cloud
- · This project will allow Nielsen's management staff to better understand their internal data and manage their complex global operations.

CONCUSSION CONNECT - ATLANTA, GA

Undergraduate Researcher

January 2017 - Present

- · Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team of Georgia Tech researchers to improve on-the-field concussion diagnosis in American football
- · Created a Microsoft Access database for years of hit testing done by the study and designed custom macros for researchers' manipulation
- · This database has been crucial for the research team to accurately analyze their tests and collaborate with the national FITBIR database

VENTURE CORPORATION LIMITED - SINGAPORE

Firmware Engineering Intern, Research & Development Department

June 2015 - July 2015

- · Worked on an interdisciplinary team to design a new and improved DNA thermocycler
- · Made meaningful impacts by analyzing the issues presented and collaborating with the team to develop the best solution for the client
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Created an intuitive and comprehensive UI with Android Studio to allow doctors to interact with the technology seamlessly and effectively}$

Projects

H.E.R.O FOR CHILDREN - ATLANTA, GA

Team Lead, Epic Intentions

January 2017 - May 2017

- · Managed an interdisciplinary team of seven Georgia Tech student volunteers in a scrum environment project creating the charity H.E.R.O. for Children's database management system
- · Spent an average of seven hours a week on the project leading the team in developing the python desktop application and MySQL database
- $\cdot\,$ The searchable database will help H.E.R.O. applying for critical grants and managing their many programs

ALLIANCE SURVIVOR RESOURCES - ATLANTA, GA

Lead Backend Developer, Epic Intentions

August 2016 – December 2016

- · Volunteered with a team of six Georgia Tech students to create web app with a MySQL database for the charity Alliance for Survivor Care
- · Responsible for leading the three-person backend development team and spent an average of five hours a week building the project
- · The web app will connect the several groups within Alliance so they can share knowledge easily with each other and the women they serve

WATER - ATLANTA, GA

CS 2340, Georgia Tech

August 2016 - December 2016

- $\cdot \ \, \text{Crowdsourced safe water location application created in response to NASA's clean water mapping challenge}$
- · Developed with a group of five Georgia Tech students in a scrum environment using JavaFx and Google Maps API
- $\cdot \ \, \text{The application is designed for people in rural areas to identify and share knowledge of safe drinking water locations}$

GT TRAVEL - BARCELONA, ES

CS 4400, Georgia Tech Barcelona Study Abroad

May 2016 - August 2016

- · Travel review application that allows users to rate and write reviews about different destinations and search based on location
- · Collaboratively developed the python GUI and MySQL database with a team of five Georgia Tech students
- $\cdot\,$ Personally responsible for leading backend development

Technical Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Python, Java, SQL, C, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, JSON, XML, and MATLAB

SOFTWARE & FRAMEWORKS

Git, Android Studio, jQuery, AngularJS, JavaFX, Bootstrap, Tkinter, Microsoft Access, SAP BusinessObjects Design Studio, SAP HANA Studio, SAP Data Services Designer, and SAP BusinessObjects Web Intelligence